Personal Profile

📱+18127785068 | 🗷 vasu.vs45@gmail.com | 🖸 github.com/vasuvs45 | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/vasu-sharma3/ | 🚨 vasu-xi.vercel.app/

Experienced professional with undergrad in Computer Science and Masters in Data Science, having more than 4 years of experience in Python, Database, Cloud technologies. Primarily looking for Software Developer/Data Engineer/Data Scientist/Data Analyst roles.

Work Experience.

DataGlacier Remote

DataScience-Intern May 2023 - Aug 2023

- · Performed an exhaustive assessment of two undisclosed cab companies, based on various factors such as customer engagement, customer reach, etc. Projected a minimal profit loss of 1.7% for this chosen company, as compared to the alternative firm's 3.5% profit loss.
- · Constructed and fine-tuned various machine learning algorithms for a bank to anticipate customer behavior for a new product launch and deployed on Flask framework.

TATRAS DATA SERVICES PRIVATE LIMITED

Delhi, India

Associate Software Engineer-Python; Client:- Good United

Feb 2022 - Aug 2022

- Utilized NLP techniques and developed a customized K-means to categorize users into clusters. Developed Python workflows using serverless architecture for a bot where different micro-services triggered and interacted with using AWS Lambda and Simple Queue Service.
- Developed a sync job in python scheduled in AWS for populating data in flat tables resulting in optimizing API response time by 70%.
- Integrated AWS Elastic cache with API to improve dashboard response time. Developed mechanisms to optimize data storage in the database leading to 75% improvement in data refresh time for materialized views through optimization techniques such as indexing and partitioning.

Globalshala Remote

Jan 2022 - Feb 2022 Data Analyst Intern

• Lead a team of 10 members on the analysis of an online ad and created dashboard on Tableau. Worked on analysis of different parameters such as Reach, Impression, Unique Clicks, Revenue etc. of ad.

Infosys Ltd. Pune, India

Senior System Engineer; Client:- Capital Group

Aug 2017 - Feb 2021

- · Lead a team of 6 members while contributing to the development of an application utilizing a step-function principle, where each step triggered a sequence of Stored Procedures. Played a key role in writing and implementing new steps, along with their corresponding stored procedures
- Implemented various reports to provide crucial insights for business users.
- Implemented APIs to obtain data from upstream and downstream data transmission and python scripts to call stored procedures.
- · Worked on queues and topics enabling seamless communication and data retrieval to other applications

Infosys Ltd. Mysore, India

Software Engineer Intern

Jan 2017 - May 2017

• Flea Market: It was online shopping and selling application where a fresh user needs to first sign in only then is he/she eligible to buy or sell products. It was developed on DOT Net MVC with SQL Database.

Technical Knowledge

Programming Languages Python (Pandas, NumPy, Pyspark, Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit, BeautifulSoup, NLTK, Matplotlib, Seaborn), C#, R

> **Database** PostgreSQL, SQL, Sybase, Amazon RedShift, MongoDB

Framework Used Flask, Django, Apache Spark, Hadoop

Cloud Services Used Amazon Web Services (Glue, Athena, SQS, RDS, DynamoDb, EC2, S3, Lambda, CloudWatch, Elastic Cache)

Tools and technologies used Tableau, Jupyter, Autosys, Atlassian tools, XL Deploy, Confluence, Pycharm, Visual Studio Code, Dbeaver, Toad

Taming Big Data with Apache Spark and Python

Data Engineering using AWS

Certifications Completed Python for DataScience and Machine Learning Bootcamp

The Python Mega Course 2022: Build 10 Real-World Pro-

Python Data Structures from University Of Michigan

Machine Learning from Stanford University

Education

Indiana University Bloomington

Bloomington,Indiana, USA

Master of Science in Data Science

Aug 2022 - May 2024

 Courses completed: Applied Algorithms, Advanced Database, Introduction to Statistic, Information Visualization, Data Mining, Stats for Effective Decision Making, Intro to Intelligent Systems, Applied Database Technologies, Management Access Use Big Data

SRM University Delhi, NCR, India

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

• Graduated with Distinction.

May 2013 - May 2017

Certifications Completed

- •Certified in Taming Big Data with Apache Spark and Python •Certified in Python DataStructures from the University Of Michigan on Coursera.
- •Completed Python for DataScience and Machine Learning Bootcamp from Udemy.